# **LEONARD TNG**

leonardtng@u.yale-nus.edu.sg • (+65) 9827 8302

I am a sophomore from Yale-NUS College with 2 years of experience in software engineering. With a mindset of curiosity and the eagerness to challenge myself, I learn fast, enjoy working in teams, and can quickly adapt to any new environment or work setting.

#### Education

## Yale-NUS College, Singapore • Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2020 - 2024

• Global Leader Scholar, CAP: 4.9/5.0

## National Junior College, Singapore • Integrated Programme • GCE 'A' Levels

2012 - 2017

MOE Pre-U Scholar, 90 Rank Points, 6 Distinctions

## Experience

## Dathena • Software Engineer Intern

May 2021 - August 2021

- Developed and enhanced key sections of the client-facing data protection dashboard that increases the product's functionality to display complex data and provide key insights. Contributions were merged into production to serve the company's clients.
- Contributed to the internal UI-library by creating reusable components, writing the documentation, and implementing unit tests. Reduces future development time and streamlines the frontend release workflow.
- Led two sprints as the scrum master of a team consisting of full-time developers. Was directly responsible for coordinating with product side and managing the development team's tasks throughout the sprint.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Redux, styled-components, D3.js, React Testing Library.

#### Boogle Group Ltd. • Software Engineer Intern

October 2019 - September 2020

- Leveraged on full-stack technologies to build and maintain a web-based MVP dashboard that allow clients to view analytics.
- Teaching assistant at NTU for a final-year web development module [BF3210] as part of an educational partnership between Boogle Group Ltd and NTU to boost the company's image and visibility.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Django REST Framework, AWS.

# Software Projects

# Saving Yale-NUS: <a href="https://www.savingyalenus.com/">https://www.savingyalenus.com/</a>

September 2021

- Collaborated with a team of students to develop a blog using static site generation that consolidates the reflections and expressions of grief from the wider student body regarding the merger of Yale-NUS College and USP.
- Implemented the main blog features and rendering of markdown files converted from input provided by Google Forms.
- <u>Utilized</u>: Next.js, TypeScript, Python, AWS (EC2).

#### Cryptoscapes: <a href="https://www.cryptoscapes.org/">https://www.cryptoscapes.org/</a>

July 2021

- Built and hosted a web-based dashboard that manipulates and displays cryptocurrency data and charts.
- Ensured efficient data flow throughout components with global state management and atomic design methodology.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Redux, AWS (S3).

#### CodeCache: https://www.codecache.io/

November 2020

- Built and hosted a web application that allows users to create, edit, delete, and view code snippets.
- Developed a RESTful API backend architecture that manages and interacts with code snippets in a MySQL database.
- Implemented token authentication and email verification via SMTP for user login and registration.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, Django REST Framework, MySQL, Docker, AWS (S3, EC2, RDS).

## Personal Website: <a href="https://www.leonardtng.com">https://www.leonardtng.com</a> (for additional information and projects)

May 2020

- Built and hosted a personal portfolio website with a responsive design and a multiple theme switcher.
- Performed search engine optimisation on website to obtain a high Google search ranking.
- <u>Utilized</u>: React.js, TypeScript, AWS (S3).

# Leadership & Clubs

# Yale-NUS Hacks (YNC\_Hacks) • Vice-President

August 2021 – Present

- Conducted two semester-long workshops on web development and a three-part React.js workshop for new members.
- Oversaw the development processes of the club's projects and facilitated project leaders to meet their project's milestones.

# Technical Skills

Programming Languages: (Proficient): TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, (Familiar): R, OCaml

Frameworks / Technologies: (*Proficient*): React.js, Next.js, Redux, Django REST Framework, (*Familiar*): React Native, Docker, MySQL Utilities: Amazon Web Services (S3, CloudFront, Route 53, EC2, ACM, Lambda, RDS), Git, GitHub, Jira, Bitbucket, Figma

Contact

Website: www.leonardtng.com • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/leonard-tng/ • GitHub: www.github.com/leonardtng